# **CANDY GARCIA**

Los Angeles, CA ne: (424) 205-4657 | Fmail: candygar

Phone: (424) 205-4657 | Email: candygarcia014@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/ | GitHub: github.com/ Portfolio:

#### **S**UMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in finance, sales, and business management. Recent graduate of the Coding Boot Camp at UCLA Extension, logging over 200 hours of classroom time and hands on coding experience. A life-long dedication to learning. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications. Known among co-workers for strong wit and attention to detail no matter the complexity of the project. Hard working above and beyond excels at every job

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript, HTML/CSS, React

Libraries / Tools: ES6, Node.js, Express, MySql, Git, jQuery, AJAX, API's, mongoDB

Applications: Heroku, Unit Testing, Microsoft Office 365, G Suite, various CRM, LinkedIn Sales Navigator, basic Yardi Voyager

knowledge

**ADDITIONAL SKILLS** 

Bilingual: Able to speak, read, and write Spanish

Sale Skills: Sales, Business Development, Business Management, Cold Calling, B2C, B2B, Networking

#### **PROJECTS**

Search and Rescue | https://github.com/candygarcia014/search-and-rescue | https://candygarcia014.github.io/search-and-rescue/ The web application helps the user find their desired pet breed in an adoption shelter nearby.

- Collaborated remotely with a team of 4 developers to design, develop, debug and deploy the web application within 1 week.
- Front end developer: built the React components and assisted with the front-end design and API routing.
- Your core responsibilities in project (1-2 lines)
- Tools / languages used

## No Gym | https://github.com/candygarcia014/NoGym https://nogym.herokuapp.com/login

Front end development

- Short summary of project (1-2 lines)
- Your core responsibilities in project (1-2 lines)
- Tools / languages used

## Self Care Pirates | Link to GitHub | Link to Deployed Project

Back end development

- Short summary of project (1-2 lines)
- Your core responsibilities in project (1-2 lines)
- Tools / languages used

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Career Strategies, Woodland Hills, CA

## Temporary Leasing Consultant

August 2020- Present

Hired as a temp to answer phones and provide quotes to prospective clients. How

ver, recognized an opportunity to increse client satisfaction and increase revenue for the company so took the initiative to Assisted the Property Manager with client services, property inspections, document filing, file audits, purchase order reviews, and reports.

• Reached 100% prospect engagement by responding promptly to phone calls and email inquiries

- Leased 10 (200% above average) luxury apartments in 25 days by assisting clients to find the appropriate home based on their budget, space needs, and timeline.
- Secured 8 renewals on average per month and brought in \$100K in revenue to the property by supporting residents
  with questions, concerns, and gave them courtesy calls about packages and rent reminders to ensure their satisfaction
  and continued residency.

## Cassette Inc, Los Angeles, CA

Office Director January 2020 – April 2020

Assisted with planning and logistics of events and conferences. Managed all outsourced vendors and contracts, from bookkeeping to legal.

- Saved the CEO and COO 10 hours of research by creating a product comparison matrix report to compare CRM's to help the decision makers select the appropriate product for the company
- Provided the employees peace of mind by sourcing an adequate health insurance plan that met their needs and personally enrolled each employee on to the company health plan.

### Northwestern Mutual, San Diego, CA

## Director of Training and Operations Coordinator for the Chief Development Officer

May 2018 – December 2019

- Generated approximately \$500K in sales quarterly revenue by directed and facilitated weekly activity coaching, monthly business development check-ins to help develop their sales skills
- Saved 80 people about 5 hours of work per week by gathering business data to compile analytical reports to track progress.
- Managed a team of three administrative team members to streamline workflow systems and increased productivity by 80% by reducing the amount of administrative work for each sales person.
- Streamlined communication and work request by 90% by designing, creating, and implementing analytical reports, templates, worksheets, work-orders, and productivity contests and incentive programs
- Provided valuable education to 100+ financial advisors of all tenures on a monthly basis by coordinating all logistics and preparing all materials for the monthly network wide meetings.

#### Northwestern Mutual, Santa Monica, CA

#### Associate Financial Representative

January 2018 - May 2018

- Produced \$150K of life insurance premiums in my first year as a financial representative by gathering, interpreting, and presenting financial analysis reports to clients in a clear and concise manner
- Serviced over 200 clients and took every measure to provide optimal customer service to ensure a long-lasting professional relationships
- Ensured the satisfaction for 100% of my clients by personally overseeing the onboarding of all the insurance and investment accounts

#### Northwestern Mutual, Los Angeles, CA

#### Financial Representative

January 2016 - December 2017

- Prospected 100 personal referrals on a monthly basis to secure my own clients: from personal introductions, cold calling, and networking
- On a monthly basis I developed and managed 30 new relationships with clients and prospective clients to build rapport and trust
- Sold Northwestern Mutual's suite of financial services and insurance products

#### Copyland, Gardena, CA

## Assistant Production Manager/ Office Manager

January 2012 – December 2015

- Directed 9 staff members using clear communication to achieve production goals to produce multimillion dollar marketing campaign products such as paper materials, web designs, graphic designs, and mai promotions.
- Trained 12 new employees on processes and policies to maintain 90% employee retention
- Processed payroll and enrolled employees into voluntary benefits and claims processing

#### **EDUCATION**

## **California State University of Long Beach**

May 2016 Bachelor of

# Minor in Human Resource Management

- Full Stack Web Development Certificate: University of California, Los Angeles, CA
   2021
- A 13-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

January